CURRICULUM VITAE

Personal Details

Name: Cynthia Aluoch Juma

Nationality: Kenyan

Telephone: +254 746 414 178

E-mail: cindiejuma@gmail.com

Personal Profile Statement

I am a highly motivated and detail-oriented statistician with a passion for data and information. I possess strong communication skills, both verbal and written, and I have more than two years of experience dealing with data. I am very organized, always ensures that the work is completed on time and can work under minimum or no supervision. I am committed to utilizing statistical theories and methods to collect, analyze, interpret and present data that will drive strategic decision-making processes.

Education and Training

a) University Education, Bachelor of Science, Applied Statistics with Computing

Moi University, Kenya

September 2015-December 2019

Attained: Second Class Upper Division

b) Secondary Education, Kenya certificate of Secondary Education

January 2011-November 2014 O-level,

Ng`iya Girls High School - Siaya, Kenya

Attained: Grade A- (Minus)

c) Primary Education, Kenya Certificate of Primary Education

January 2003 –November 2010

Siaya Township Primary School, Siaya, Kenya

Professional and Work Experience

Tamuwa Limited Associate Data Analyst

Oct 2024- Current

Duties and responsibilities

- Ensure accurate data entry, review, and approval in ERP systems, maintaining up-to-date and accessible information.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to uphold data integrity and resolve discrepancies effectively.
- Streamline workflows to enhance data retrieval efficiency and operational processes.
- Provide training and support for ERP systems, Metabase, and other technical tools.

- Extract and analyze data in Metabase to generate actionable insights and operational reports.
- Prepare reports, maintain records, develop SOPs, and manage project logistics and data activities.

Kenya Medical Research Institute (KEMRI- CGHR) Assistant Data manager

April 2024 – Sep 2024

Duties and responsibilities

- Study data management and filing.
- Updating participant information in the database.
- Archiving data and ensuring proper storage and maintenance of data.
- Ensuring data quality, verification, accuracy and validity.
- Analysis of quality indicators.
- Ensuring accurate and timely data entry.

ASA International Kenya Limited Loan officer.

Jan 2022- Mar 2024

Duties and Responsibilities

- Collecting and reviewing loan applications, financial documents and creditworthiness of applicant
- Analyze applicants' credit histories, income and debt.
- Evaluate risk associated with each loan applicant and decide whether to approve loan or deny.
- Keeping applicants informed about loan policy and how to manage their loans.
- Preparing and organizing loan documents, contracts and agreements.
- Making sure all records are accurate, up-to-date and well maintained.

Malaria Project (EPI-003 and EPI-005) under CDC-KEMRI and MOH April 2019

Casual Data Clerk

Duties and responsibilities

- Digitizing records of Ministry of Health (MoH) registers using Epi-info.
- Ensuring data security and confidentiality is maintained.
- Completing data entry progress reporting form and registers tracker form.

KEMRI, RCTP-FACES Program, Kisumu, Kenya Attachment (Statistician)

Jan 2019 - Mar 2019

Duties and responsibilities

- Designing and testing data collection tools according to required documentation using specified tools like Kobo collect, Open Data Kit and REDCap.
- Conducting data management using traditional statistical tools like STATA and SPSS by utilizing wide-long reshape techniques, EGEN methods, among others.
- Conducting data quality audits by doing triangulation of Electronic Medical Records (EMR) and paper records to ascertain data quality issues like missing data, inaccuracies, inconsistent values among other pre-specified data quality aspects.

• Conducting basic data analysis using available statistical packages and MS Excel and running frequency tables and simple regression analysis like linear and logistic regressions.

Jamat Cyber Café and Computer College, Siaya, Kenya Cybercafé assistant and computer tutor

Sept 2016 – Jan 2017

Duties and responsibilities

- Assisting clients and helping with activities that involve using internet. Help customers with the use of computers and applications.
- Assist client's complete forms and returns for KRA, NTSA, NHIF and other e returns.
- Assist customers with downloads, printing, scanning and emailing documents.
- Teaching students the basic computer packages theoretically and practically.
- Assessing the students.

Additional information

Reading, Research, swimming, Travelling, Fitness, Voluntary Work

Referees

1. Sir Ben Odhiambo

TB Data manager KEMRI- CGHR, P.O. BOX 1578- 40100

Mobile phone: +254 723902262 Email: BOOdhiambo@kemri.go.ke

2. Sir Benard Ochieng Samba

Lead Biostatistician

KEMRI- Family AIDS Care and Education Services (FACES) Program,

P.O BOX 614-40100

Mobile phone: +254 729355595 Email: ben32samba@gmail.com

3. Sir Isaiah Omondi

Data manager KEMRI- Malaria branch P.O. BOX 1578- 40100

Mobile phone: +254 713 456124 Email: iomondi19@gmail.com